Mss.B.F867
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 28, 1884; B F867.9; 8x5-1/2; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 3p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning the B.A.A.S. members who plan to attend the A.A.A.S.meeting in Philadelphia. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 29, 1884; McKendrik, John G.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 30, 1884; Marshall, William P.
    Plans to attend the meeting along with his son (Dr. Marshall of Manchester).
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, July 31, 1884; Saunders, Trelawney
    Plans to attend the meeting and will talk about the census of India (which may be interesting in light of the publication of the U.S. census). May also address Biblical Geography (in communication with Rev. Dr. Clay Trumbull to discuss a possible lecture).
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, [July, 1884]; King, E. M.
    Discussion of travel plans from Liverpool to Canada and then Philadelphia for the meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 4, 1884; Fewings, James
    Plans to attend the meeting with a traveling companion.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 7, 1884; Stewart, George, Jr.
    Plans to attend the meeting along with two other couples.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 7, 1884; Worthington, A. W.
    Plans to attend the meeting; is attempting to arrange for his daughter to attend as well.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 8, 1884; Gisborne, F. N.
    2 items: Plans to attend the meeting with his wife (Canadian Government Telegraph Service letterhead); requests hotel information (small card).
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 10, 1884; Heath, Thomas
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 11, 1884; B F867.9; 10x7-3/4; Hall, James, 1811-1898
    Gloucester, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Will go to Montreal to meet the B.A.A.S. and then to Philadelphia to meet the A.A.A.S. Will send one or two papers this fall. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 11, 1884; Brown, John
    Plans to attend the meeting, accompanied by his wife.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 11, 1884; Hubbet, R. G.
    2 items: Letter stating intent to attend the meeting (on British Association for the Advancement of Science Montreal Meeting letterhead) and an envelope with Frazer's pre-printed address.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 13, 1884; Ravenstein, Ernest, 1834-1913
    Plans to attend the meeting; his wife will also attend.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 14, 1884; Carver, Alfred J.
    2 items. Calling card for Rev. Canon Carver, D.D. (with handwritten note: "lately "Master of Dulwich College"") and a letter communicating his intention to attend the meeting along with his wife and daughters Constance and Ethel.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 14, 1884; Nutt, Lilian M.
    Apologizes that she will not, in fact, be able to accept the invitation.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 14, 1884; Woodall, John W.
    Handwritten letter re: Mr. Laughton's invitation.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 15, 1884; King, E. M.
    Plans to attend the meting with another woman. If papers may be read, she would be happy to present on the subject of "rational dress" with a scientific slant.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 16, 1884; Barker, Jessie M.
    Plans to attend the meeting with a friend.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 16, 1884; Dallinger, W. H., (William Henry)
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 17, 1884; Craigie, P. G.
    Plans to attend the meeting. Craigie's letter, written in ink, is followed on the same sheet by a penciled note by another author (Frank M. Etting?).
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 17, 1884; Mulhall, Michael G.
    Mulhall, a statistician, plans to attend the meeting along with his wife (also a member of the British Association and author of "Between the Amazon and the Andes").
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 18, 1884; Pim, Bedford
    Plans to attend meeting and has finalized his list of six traveling companions.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 19, 1884; Pim, Bedford
    Two pages: A note that Pim fears his letter of the 18th may not have been received, and a substantive copy of same (noting his intention to attend the meeting along with guests).
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 20, 1884; Brown, John
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 21, 1884; Briggs, Arthur
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 23, 1884; Loudon, J.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 25, 1884; Harley, George
    Will be unable to attend the meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 26, 1884; Stewardson, J. H.
    2 items: A note on letterhead that Stewardson has enclosed information for attending members is enclosed; a separate sheet lists Benjamin Francis Conn Costelloe's degrees, posts, address.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 26, 1884; Brown, H. Binney
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 27, 1884; Baker, John
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 27, 1884; Dobson, G. E.
    Regretfully declines the invitation, as he will be in the Rocky Mountains and won't visit Philadelphia until the middle of September.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 27, 1884; Seville, Thomas
    Schedule only permits a brief visit near the close of the meeting, so rooms need not be held for Seville and his wife.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 27, 1884; Weldon, Walter, 1832-1885
    2 items: calling card and a letter thanking Frazer for the rooms reserved at the Continental Hotel.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 27, 1884; Worthington, A. W.
    Travel plans do not permit him to visit Philadelphia so soon after the Montreal conference, and has advised the hotel he and his daughter will not be using the rooms reserved.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 28, 1884; Briggs, Arthur
    Discuss plans to meet.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 28, 1884; Dowling, J. F.
    Plans to attend, apologizes for the late notice, and requests to stay with his friend Samuel Spruce.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 28, 1884; Marshall, A. Milnes
    Thanks for arranging for rooms at the Continental, hopes to arrive for the opening of the meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 28, 1884; Ommanney, Erasmus
    2 items: calling card (with "CB" and "FRS" added by hand) and a note declining the invitation.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 28, 1884; Pegler, Alfred
    2 items: envelope and note acknowledging hotel booking and inquiring whether he must pay expenses or if he is a guest.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 28, 1884; Pullar, Robert
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 28, 1884; Pullar, Rufus D.
    Plans to attend and will advise the Continental Hotel what dates he will need his room.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 28, 1884; Salt, Shirley H.
    Has been in contact with the hotel regarding her arrival date.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 28, 1884; Spanton, W. Dunnett
    Will be unable to attend as Mr. [Ailidge?] must return to England sooner than expected.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 28, 1884; Spruce, Samuel
    Hopes to attend along with Dowling (a recent member of the B.A.A.)
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 28, 1884; Cooke Taylor, R. W.
    Appreciates the arrangements, arrival will now be delayed until the 7th or 8th.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 28, 1884; Trail, James W. H.
    Regrets that he and his wife will not be able to attend the meeting as previously expected.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 29, 1884; Carver, Alfred J.
    Travel and lodging arrangement at the Colonnade Hotel for Carver, his wife, and two daughters for the meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 29, 1884; Durham, Thomas
    Traveling with his daughter, not wife; requests that this be corrected with the hotel.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 29, 1884; Fewings, James
    Will arrive with a friend on Monday the 8th of September and requests assistance with lodging.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 29, 1884; Haddon, Alfred C. (Alfred Cort), 1855-1940.
    Plans to attend and will communicate directly with the Bellevue Hotel.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 29, 1884; Mulhall, Michael G.
    Regrets not seeing Frazer before his 8/28 departure, looks forward to seeing him in Philadelphia and has advised the Colonnade of his travel plans.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 29, 1884; Ommanney, Erasmus
    2 items: evelope and letter declining the invitation since, as an officer of the Association, he does not feel able to leave Montreal in time.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 29, 1884; Rideal, Samuel
    Plans to arrive in Philadelphia the following Thursday, and has advised the Contintental Hotel.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 29, 1884; Robertson, Geo[rge] H.
    Declines offer of hotel room as he cannot visit Philadelphia in time for the meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 29, 1884; Saunders, Howard
    Declines offer of hosptiality for the Philadelphia meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 29, 1884; Spanton, W. Dunnett
    Plans to attend with a different friend (not [Ailidge?]) and their arrival and departure times are not yet fixed.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 30, 1884; Craigie, P. G.
    Regrets missing Frazer in person, occupied with "the business of my Section "7"."
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 30, 1884; ----, ----
    Unsigned letter regarding "hospitality" offered in Philadelphia (e.g. who will pay visitors' room and board).
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Friday, 1884; Bevan, J. O. (James Oliver)
    Will be accepting Rev. E. Whitall's hospitality for the meeting in Philadelphia.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, [Summer, 1884]; King, E. M.
    Requests a reply, references room 552.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, [Summer, 1884]; Marshall, William P.
    Plans to attend the meeting, as does his son.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, [Summer, 1884]; Trail, James W. H.
    Written on behalf of Trail and his wife, who plan to attend the meeting.
  - Envelopes addressed to Persifor Frazer, [Summer, 1884]; Briggs, Arthur; McKendrik, John G.; Wrightson, Thomas
    4 items. Envelopes addressed to Persifor Frazer. Handwritten notes regarding senders (Briggs, Wrightson, McKendrick and Mrs. H. Binney Brown?) and replies.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 1, 1884; Baynes, Robert E.
    Discusses logistics (5:55 PM arrival on Friday), requests that tickets to the Presidential address be given to R. Pearsall Smith (his host in Philadelphia), advises of his intention to register the following morning.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 1, 1884; Cotterill, James H.
    Hotel is unnecessary, after being invited to lodge with Dr. Levick.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 1, 1884; Hudson, William H. H.
    Addresses apparent discrepancy in hotel reservations, announces plans to be at the Hotel Lafayette on Wednesday or Thursday.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 1, 1884; Ommanney, Erasmus
    Will be able to attend the meeting in Philadelphia, and requests accommodations for himself and his son.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 2, 1884; Carver, Alfred J.
    Carver's son (Arthur Wellington Carver) will now also be coming to the meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 2, 1884; Le Neve Foster, C.
    Plans to attend the meeting, will accept offer of hospitality if it is still available.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 2, 1884; Lister, Thomas
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 2, 1884; Westwood Oliver, J. A.
    Will not be able to attend the meeting because of an excursion to the Rocky Mountains.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 2, 1884; B F867.9; 5-1/2x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 3p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Has been ill. Will come to Philadelphia. Concerning geologists, among whom are James Hall and James Geikie. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 2, 1884; Ommanney, Erasmus
    Detailing travel plans to Philadelphia.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 2, 1884; Slattery, James W.
    Plans to attend the meeting, requests a "good sized room with bath."
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 3, 1884; Hayward, Robert B.
    Writing on behalf of his brother-in-law (Rev. H. W. [Coulson]?) who has been delayed in England and thus unable to attend the meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, [September 3?], 1884; Story, James
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 5, 1884; Taylor, C.
    Writes to advise he has arrived in his hotel in Philadelphia (but, like some other travelers, his baggage has been delayed).
  - Letter to Persifor Frazier [sic], September 6, 1884; B F867.9; 6x5; Leidy, Joseph, jr.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. (see P.Frazer Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Thanks him for a favor. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Mrs. Persifor Frazer, September 7, 1884; Pim, Bedford
    Writes to accept a dinner invitation.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 7, 1884; Ross, W. A.
    2 items: calling card, letter complaining of the prices and service at the Continental Hotel.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 15, 1884; B F867.9; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Asks that his mail be forwarded to Montreal. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, September 26, 1884; B F867.9; 6x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 6p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Friendly letter. Looks for asbestos mines. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, [September, 1884]; Taylor, C.
    2 items: calling card ("The Master of St. John's College" is crossed out, and "Rev. C. Taylor DD." and "Cambridge, England" written by hand), and letter stating intent to attend the meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, October 2, 1884; Ommanney, Erasmus
    Offers thanks for hospitality while in Philadelphia, some details of his subsequent travels.
  - Abstract of address, [1884]; Suess, Edward
    Abstract of address before the Congress, per penciled note.
  - Calling card, [1884?]; Mactear, J.
    Lt. Col.'s calling card, "Glasgow" added by hand.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, March 14, 1885; B F867.9; 7x4-1/2; Geikie, James, 1839-1915
    Edinburgh A.L.S. 4p. (see P.Frazer. Lettres from various persons; 1883-1885.) Describes his work. Concerning current events in England. Friendly letter. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, April 6, 1885; B F867.9; 7-3/4x5-1/4, 2-1/2x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 3p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Friendly letter. Concerning the study of mineralogy. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, May 1, 1885; B F867.9; 8x5-1/4; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Montreal, A.L.S. 2p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning his plans for travel. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, May 26, 1885; B F867.9; 8x4-3/4; Geikie, James, 1839-1915
    Edinburgh A.L.S. 4p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning his plans for the next few months. Sends doggerel verse on "To my Alma Mater on the completion of her 300th year." Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, August 14, 1885; B F867.9; 8x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Boston, A.L.S. 3p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning his travels. Glad the photograph was sent to Frazer. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, August 29, 1885; B F867.9; 8x5; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Ann Arbor, A.L.S. 4p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning certain business of the A.A.A.S. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Mac [sic] Frazer, September 14, 1885; B F867.9; 6x4; Geikie, James, 1839-1915
    Edinburgh, A.L.S. 4p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Is delighted that he is in England, but cannot see him until October. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to [Persifor Frazer], October 14, 1885; B F867.9; 7x4-1/2; Geikie, James, 1839-1915
    Edinburgh A.L.S. 2p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Looks forward to his visit the latter part of October. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to [Persifor Frazer], October 30, 1885; B F867.9; 8x5; Geikie, James, 1839-1915
    A.L.S. 1p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Wants him to come and visit. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to [Persifor Frazer], November 5, 1885; B F867.9; 7x4-1/2; Geikie, James, 1839-1915
    A.L.S. 3p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Is sorry that they could not meet. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to [Persifor Frazer], December 1, 1885; B F867.9; 8x5; Hayden, Ferdinand Vandiveer, 1829-1887
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Is sorry that, due to ill health, he cannot visit Frazer. Formerly B F867.9.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, May 17, 1891; B F867.4; 9-1/4x5-1/2; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    1958 2255ms
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. (see Persifor Frazer papers. No.4.) Asks for some information. Concerning his paper on mineralogy. Formerly B F867.4.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 1 (?), 1891; B F867.3; 7x4-1/2; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    1958 2254ms
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. (see Persifor Frazer papers. No. 3.) Thanks for, and praises of, his publication on mineralogy. Will soon send his new publication. Formerly B F867.3.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Philadelphia, April 14, 1901; B F867.5; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Haeckel, Ernst Heinrich Philipp August, 1834-1919
    1958 2256ms
    Baden-Baden, A.L.S.on postal card. 1p.and add. In German. (see Persifor Frazer papers. No. 5.) FILM 403 FRAME 110. Formerly B F867.5.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Philadelphia, April 4, 1902; B F867.8; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Haeckel, Ernst Heinrich Philipp August, 1834-1919
    1958 2259ms
    Jena, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In German. (see Persifor Frazer papers. No. 8.) FILM 403 FRAME 111. Formerly B F867.8.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Philadelphia, October 27, 1902; B F867.7; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Haeckel, Ernst Heinrich Philipp August, 1834-1919
    1958 2258ms
    Jena, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In German. (see Persifor Frazer papers. No. 7.) FILM 403 FRAME 112. Formerly B F867.7.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Philadelphia, February 25, 1906; B F867.6; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Haeckel, Ernst Heinrich Philipp August, 1834-1919
    1958 2257ms
    Jena, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In German.(see Persifor Frazer papers. No. 6.) Concerning the 200th anniversary of Franklin. Refers to the APS. FILM 403 FRAME 113. Formerly B F867.6.
  - Letter to [Persifor Frazer], undated; B F867.9; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Hayden, Ferdinand Vandiveer, 1829-1887
    Thursday. A.L.S.with initials. (see P.Frazer. Letters from various persons; 1883-1885.) Concerning the list of persons for candidates. Concerning a publication on obelisks. Formerly B F867.9.